

Saugat Maharjan UI/UX Designer | IT Engineer

🔀 saugatmaharjan11@gmail.com 🤳 +977-9843687180

• Dhalko-17, Kathmandu

Profile

from Kathmandu, Nepal. I design and craft products to provide visual experiences from the user research to the high-fidelity design with more than a years of experience. My interest in design field sparked during pursuing my bachelors degree. Apart from my interest in technology, I have a passion for

I'm a passionate UI/UX Designer with an Engineering Degree

traveling, drawing, playing video games, listening to music, learning new things, and taking on thrilling challenges. Additionally, I consider myself a food enthusiast who enjoys trying out different cuisines at all times.

Mid UI/UX Designer EKbana Solutions, Jwagal

Experience

Freelance Designer [Part-time] Aug 2023 - Jan 2024

Jan 2024 - Present

Pursuing

2015

Jun 2022

Aug 2022

Sep 2022

Oct 2022

Dec 2022

SCSS Consulting

Product Designer May 2022 - Dec 2023

GlobalyHub, Kumaripati, Lalitpur

Design Intern Dec 2021 - Apr 2022

GlobalyHub, Kumaripati, Lalitpur

Education

Masters in Business Administration

Herald College, Naxal Bhagwati

Affiliated to Pokhara University

Affiliated to University of Wolverhampton

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology 2017 - 2022 CGPA - 3.07

Nepal College of Information Technology, Balkumari, Lalitpur

Higher Secondary Education 2015 - 2017 65.90% - First Division

Kathmandu Model College, Bagbazzar, Kathmandu

80.38% - First Division with Distinction Maha Manjushree H.S School, Sitapaila, Kathamndu

Foundations of User Experience (UX)

School Leaving Certificate

Certificates

Credential ID: R5JKTCWJFARF

Design

Start the UX Design Process: Jul 2022 **Empathize, Define and Ideate** Credential ID: QUMJGP9MUCES

Prototypes Credential ID: 9643NENPDM6J

Create High-Fidelity Designs and

Responsive Web Design in Adobe XD

Conduct UX Research and Test Early

Build Wireframes and Low-Fidelity

Concepts Credential ID: V3D9G84SHKTG

Prototypes in Figma Credential ID: YRNQESVB83D7

Credential ID : JLCLUVGQ8CB7

Designed the GlobalyHub website from scratch to fully

• Deployed website using Webflow - learned from scratch.

• Website design revamp aligning with the brand guidelines.

responsive implementing Design System.

Agentcis Design System, Components & Variants, User Interface, User

Real-Time Projects

Experience

SCSS Consulting

GlobalyHub Website

OA Online Attendance - Case Study 2023 **NepaWatch - Website for Smartwatch**

UI Travel Kit Travel App - Figma

Ghumfir - Case Study 2022

View More in Portfolio

Academic Projects

Minor Project (6th semester) Github - Code

Second Position on Men's Cricket Feb 2020

Held on occassion od Annual Sports Day by NCIT college.

 Received cash prize for being topper in IT department in NCIT college in 8th semester. Received cash prize for being topper in IT department in NCIT

- Kathmandu Model College.
- Reference

Flower Catalogue App Flower Catalogue App for Trendy Florist - Case Study

Ghumfir Employee Task Management Employee Task Management - Figma

NepaWatch - Case Study

Gamified Healthy Eating App

Gamified Healthy Eating App - Case Study

Ghumfir: Companion Finder as

an UI/UX Designer

Ghumfir - Figma

Major Project (8th semester)

Python and Django

Achievements

First Project (4th semester)

Smart Travel Planning Application using Flutter with Dart

Library Management System using

First position in Inter-house Football

Annual sports week held by school.

college in 5th semester.

AAERI Nepal Hobbies Developed and hosted the website using Wix Builder. Travelling **OHC Guide** Drawing • Implemented Design System, Components & Variants, Refactored design following Auto-Layout Video Games Extending and Managing Product Features, Creating User ■ Football, Futsal Interface and User Experience • Website Revamp [Design, Copywriter, Development (HTML, ■ Music, Movies CSS, JS)]. Developed and hosted in Wix Builder in present. **Professional Projects OA Online Attendance App** 2023

www.saugatmaharjan.com

Website

Linkedin

Personal Details

https://www.linkedin.com/ in/saugat-

Nationality Nepali

maharjan-471a86225/

Permanent Address

Kathmandu, Nepal

Adobe XD Illustrator

Figma

Photoshop

Webflow

SCSS / Tailwind / Bootstrap

JS

HTML / CSS

Qualities

Active Person, Problem-

Solving, Persevering,

■ Compatible and Friendly,

■ Strong ability to balance

multiple priorities with

■ Excellent oral and written

presentation skills, ability

communication and

to communicate

Reliable, Flexible.

Teamwork and

Collaborations. Analytical Thinking.

management skills. Ability to lead and work well in teams.

excellent time

confidently.

Exploring and Learning History

Nepali

Newari

Languages

English

Hindi

2023

2023

2022

2022

2021

2020

2019

Feb 2014

Received Scholarship to study Intermediate (+2 Science) program for securing good marks in entrance exam at Awarded by Kilagha Twa: for securing Distinction position among SLC candidates on 5th December 2015.

- **Ashish Dhakal** Design Manager, GlobalyHub | Freelance Toptal Designer estadhakal8888@gmail.com
- Product Manager, GlobalyHub sebika07@gmail.com

9808884693

9849415848

Sebika Shrestha